In this video, we're going to look at the issue of training deep autoencoders.
在这一讲的视频中 我们将要探讨 深度自编码训练中的一些问题
People thought of these a long time ago, in the mid 1980s.
人们在很久以前 大概20世纪80年代中期 就已经在考虑这些问题了
But they simply couldn't train them well enough for them to do significantly
但是他们不能很好地进行训练
better than principal components analysis.
使深度自编码的效果能够 显著地超越主成分分析
There were various papers published about them, but no good demonstrations of
有很多关于这些问题的论文被发表但是 没有一种方法表现出令人印象深刻的性能
impressive performance. After we developed methods of
在我们研发了一次预训练一层神经网络
pre-training deep networks one layer at a time.
的方法之后
Russ Salakhutdinov and I applied these methods to pretraining deep autoencoders,
Russ Salakhutdinov和我应用这些 方法来预训练深度自编码神经网络
and for the first time, we got much better representations out of deep
并且第一次获得了比主成分分析更好的
autoencoders than we could get from principal components analysis.
深度自编码表示
Deep autoencoders always seemed like a really nice way to do dimensionality
深度自编码网络经常看上去 像是一个很好的降维方法
reduction because it seemed like they should work much better than principal
因为表面上看它们似乎 应该比主成分分析工作得更好
components analysis. They provide flexible mappings in both
它们提供了灵活的双向映射机制
directions, and the mappings can be non-linear.
并且这种映射可以是非线性的
Their learning time should be linear or better in the number of training cases.
它们的学习时间复杂度应该是线性的 或者在某些情况下 是优于线性的
And after they've been learned, the encoding part of the network is fairly
在学习完毕之后 网络中的编码过程是相当快速的
fast because it's just a matrix multiplier for each layer.
因为这只是每一层网络的 一次矩阵乘法运算而已
Unfortunately, it was very difficult to optimize deep autoencoders using back
不幸的是 使用后向传播算法 优化深度自编码网络
propagation. Typically people try small initial
是非常困难的 比较典型的做法 就是人们尝试使用小的初始权重
weights, and then the back propagated gradient died, so for deep network, they
然后 与深度网络一样 后向传播梯度失败
never got off the ground. But now we have much better way to
他们永远也没有成功 但是现在我们有更好的方法
optimize them. We can use unsupervised layer by layer
来优化它们 我们可以使用非监督的、以层为单位的
pre-training, or we can simply initialize the weight
预训练 或者我们可以更聪明地初始化权重
sensibly, as an echo statement it works. The first really successful deep water
就像echo语句一样工作 第一个成功的深水编码网络
encoders were learned by Russ Salakhutdinov and I in 2006.
由Russ Salakhutdinov和我在2006年训练成功
We applied them to the N-ness digits. So we started with images with 784
我们将它们应用在了数字编码中 我们从784个像素的数字入手
pixels. And we then encoded those via three
之后我们使用三个隐藏层
hidden layers, into 30 real valued activities in a central code layer.
将它们在中间层编码成30个实数单元
We then decoded those 30 real valued activities,
然后我们将这30个实数单元解码成
back to 784 reconstructed pixels. We used a stack of restricted Boltzmann
784个重构的像素点 我们使用一叠受限玻尔兹曼机
machine to initialize the weights used for encoding,
来初始化编码的权重
and we then took the transposers of those weights and initialized the decoding
然后我们使用那些权重的转置 来初始化解码网络
network with them. So initially, the 784 pixels were
因此 这784个像素点在一开始
reconstructed, using a weight matrix that was just the transpose of the weight
就通过一个权重矩阵进行了重构 该矩阵只是编码网络的
matrix used for encoding them. But after the four restricted Boltzmann
权重矩阵的转置 但是在四个受限玻尔兹曼机
machines have being trained and unrolled to give the transposes for decoding,
被训练以及展开 从而得到用于解码的转置矩阵之后
we then applied back propagation to minimize the reconstruction error of the
我们应用后向传播算法来最小化
784 pixels. In this case we were using a
这784个像素点的重构误差 在这里我们使用交叉熵误差
cross-entropy error, because the pixels were represented by logistic units.
因为这些像素点被表示成了逻辑斯蒂单元
So that error was back propagated through this whole deep net.
因此这些误差被后向传播到整个网络
And we once started back propagating the error,
我们一旦开始后向传播这些误差
the weights used for reconstructing the pixels became different from the weights
用于重构像素点的权重 将会变得和编码这些像素点的权重不同
used for encoding the pixels. Although they, typically stayed fairly
尽管看上去它们很相似
similar. This worked very well.
这工作的非常好
So if you look at the first row, that's one random sample from each digit class.
因此 如果你看第一行 这是从每个数字类别中随机抽样出来的数字
If you look at the second row, that's the reconstruction of the random sample by
如果你看第二行 这是由深度自编码网络
the deep autoencoder that uses 30 linear hidden units in its central layer.
利用中间层中30个线性隐藏神经元 重构完的上一行中对应的数字
So the data has been compressed to 30 real numbers and then reconstructed.
数据被压缩成30个实数然后进行重构
If you look at the eight, you can see that the reconstruction is actually
如果你看一下8这个数字 你会发现重构出的8
better than the eight. It's got rid of the little defect in the
更加的好 它摆脱了原始8中的瑕疵
eight because it doesn't have the capacity to encode it.
因为它并没有编码这一瑕疵的能力
If you compare that with linear principal commands analysis, you can see it's much
如果你和线性主成分分析进行比较 你会发现这一方法更好
better. A linear mapping to 30 real numbers
一个到30个实数的线性映射
cannot do nearly as good a job of representing the data.
并不能工作地像它表示这些数据一样好 翻译：Lyndon Li